hello my name is green and i am back
from my travels i have been away for a
week and there's lots of things that i
need to do
and one of them is restock dig straight
down look at this there's only three
places left this is the mini game that i
made a couple of episodes ago and it has
been raking in the diamonds however it
ended up costing me probably about the
same amount that i was making
so what i saw in the comments was a
bunch of suggestions that could save me
some diamonds so what we're going to do
is try out this suggestion first to see
if it works so this game really is
supposed to be a game of chance for me
and for the people that play however it
was pointed out that we might be able to
save some of the diamonds by adding a
hopper
and then adding a sign
like so and then adding a bucket of lava
above the sign but i don't want the
hermits to think that i'm trying to
swindle them out of diamonds this game
is foremost a mind game of when you
think the lava is going to hit but to
get some of the diamonds back would be
really really handy so i'm gonna get
some lava and we're gonna try this out
so in theory if we add the lava right
there what happens is they fall down and
they sink through just enough so the
bottom half is here they're taking
damage
and i might actually have to try two
versions of this to see which one yields
the best results so we got two to test
out we've got one with just one gap and
here with two so let's try number one uh
i so i've got 15 blocks
and i'm going to spread them out like
that and i'm gonna fall down and i'm
just gonna let it take
oh wow that was quick so now we need to
check
how many of those actually survived
one
one and the zeit so we're going to try
it again it looks like my inventory is
actually empty it's not there's lots of
light gray stained glass paint that is a
real pain to say
and we're going to see if the second one
yields better results but i don't want
people to be able to survive that's the
thing so they fall yeah you can just you
survive if you do this so this doesn't
work very well i will add a hopper
anyway because even if it saves two or
three diamonds that's better than
nothing i've got all of them planned out
and some of them have quite a lot in and
others have none there's one of them
with absolutely none in one of them has
over 15 diamonds in this time so there's
big risk reward on this one i've got to
empty the chests
and then make my way down
who did that
oh my goodness well i'm pretty sure i
can survive in lava for a pretty long
time but
jeez i definitely will not be resetting
this in a hurry it took nearly an hour
just to put all of the diamonds and
stuff there is a lot more reward this
time there's
one
diamond block somewhere in here
and
i think that that will realistically get
you over 13 diamonds which is pretty
good so i'll let the hermits know that
it is redone and ready to go again i
will need to restock these but i'll do
that a little bit later on because there
are plenty of other things that i want
to be getting on with this episode i've
got a big old list of things that i need
to do and one of them is actually to
introduce our very first
food store in hermitland it is going to
be sahara related which is why i've got
a bunch of shulker boxes with me and
i've actually got two boxes of golden
carrots what i'm going to do is uh sell
what i'm going to do is sell the best
food in the game which is golden carrots
but at a really cheap price so you can
get two stacks of golden carrots for one
diamond i may even make it three stacks
i don't know
however the issue is though that you've
got to come all the way over to
hermitland to buy it but if you're here
hopefully we could get a few sales
because there's quite a lot of golden
carrots here so i've got my white
concrete i've got my cyan terracotta
let's do a quick time lapse of making
this little food stand and while we're
at it i think i'm going to make a few
improvements to this little bridge here
and start tidying up this area and
hopefully encourage others to start
developing it up as well so what we're
going to be making is a very small
sahara themed shop using our very
favorite colors our cyan terracotta our
white concrete and of course i've got to
stick the architect logo in there and
then the sign for the shop itself very
very simple but there's not a lot of
space around here so i think it's a
perfect location for this kind of thing
and hopefully it can encourage some of
the herba hermits as for the bridge
honestly the shape as it went down it
works quite well it goes straight over
the water so what i wanted to do is just
make it look a little better it was
looking very unfinished so i just wanted
to tidy it up a little bit in terms of
you know adding some arches on the sides
and making it look a bit more integrated
into the landscape and also attach it to
the sign as well there will be more and
more improvements to come over time this
is a bit of a steady project
to work on over time so i fixed the
bridge up and i made it cleaner but by
cleaner i also made it mixed brick which
can also make it look a bit older and
well more worn down however hermit land
doesn't really have a theme so to speak
i'm hoping that it's going to be a
patchwork of
thing things like this
this looks like another mini game that's
popped up next to dig straight down
so i tied this up and i added this
which is sahara eats it's an architect
project so we've got two shulker boxes
full of golden carrots and all i've got
to do now is add a couple of signs
there we go welcome to sahara eats an
architect company
two stacks of golden carrots for one
diamond and i actually saw that there's
a game over here made by scar
which is basically hide and seek which
i'm really hoping that we can play later
but obviously can't play hide and seek
by yourself so hopefully scar will be
around later and we can give that game a
go this on the other hand i need to read
up on welcome to let it rip the object
of the game is to jump from the top and
bounce off the slimebox as high as you
can at the top of your bounce land on
the scaffolding and see how high you can
make well
you can't get very high i'm guessing
this is the limit 38 is the limit
unless it's raining and 128
might be exactly how high this is
in the first place yeah so the top of
this is 128 so i i automatically can't
beat the score that's in there already
but it's a nice little mini game that's
been added to the district the other
thing is i actually have been flattening
this area over here because i have
another mini game which i'm going to add
but we're going to do that a bit later
on but we're actually going to do that a
little bit later on there's still a lot
of prep work that's going to go into
this one this game that i'm gonna be
making here is actually bigger than dig
straight down but i actually wanted to
go and check and get my time machine
back from
over here somewhere
i left it in this area
because it was a bit of a pain to move
oh
hold on
what is this this looks very police-like
big line of wool
it goes
over the mountains wow this is a huge
area oh my goodness
what's all this about
one of the hermits is doing something
but i left my time machine
somewhere around here
and villager grien's in there as well so
i've got to get him back
i can't remember exactly where i left it
whoa
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
wait oh no
i'm pretty that that might be where i
left it but it's not there
oh i don't know if i should i don't know
if i should go in here
i mean that that that there the yellow
and black line that's a do not enter
kind of line but i do want to check
where my time machine is
it's not here
that's definitely time machine shaped
maybe somebody no no one could have used
it because i took the power source out
hmm
i think i'm putting
putting the puzzle pieces together here
guys the time machine
has been taken into
wow i mean that is an awesome looking
build that is amazing look at that it's
got a tower hanger 18 no trespassing
military installation photography is
prohibited
oh yeah
look at this
screenshot
[Laughter]
restricted area no trespassing beyond
this point oh my goodness
this is like this is like pretty spooky
looking
and look at that look
that's the thing that was flying in the
shopping district that had absolutely
nothing in is my
is my time machine
in this yard it doesn't it doesn't look
like it maybe we can take a little fly
over that's not trespassing
nope nothing in there i reckon they've
got it i reckon they've got it whoever's
made this
whoever's responsible for this build has
got my time machine
and i want but more importantly they've
got village agreeing which we're gonna
have to get back at some point maybe
it's kerb or iskall i need to find out
who's responsible for that before i try
and get my time machine back you don't
want to mess with the wrong hermit we'll
find out what's going on there a little
bit later because iskall has just come
online and we were talking about having
a little meeting with the other
architects
to find out what we're going to do next
with sahara so i think i'm going to head
back to the old lands
and see if we can't meet up with him
we're um where where is he on his way
have you spoken with him where's mumbo
mumbo's yeah
this isn't the first time that he's not
showed up to a meeting
yeah i know this is good this is getting
standard to be fair
architects is just me and you at the
moment
i wonder what we have to do to get him
to meeting it just leave a trail of
redstone to his to his to his chair yeah
yeah like hanson greta no
you know what we we we're not gonna put
up with this i know i know something
that will remind him
to
come to meetings and we can we can we
could get him here come on follow me
follow me follow me all right all right
come to my base i think you'll know
exactly what i'm gonna do
oh he's not gonna be happy okay he's not
gonna be happy
yes
this is a good idea oh man it's been a
long time since i've used this i reckon
what we do is we take his mustache and
we just put that in the meeting that way
[Laughter]
he's there in spirit all right let's
let's just play let's just play i'm not
paying for my own mustache machine
no no don't be silly
[Music]
take that mustache away
[Laughter]
doesn't get old and
it should be
right on here there we go oh my goodness
there he is
there it is oh
that's that's such a you can clearly
tell it's it's mustache it's oiled it's
waxed it's perfect we could take this
anywhere
it's like a mobile mustache
i love it
all right
all right now we can put him in the
meeting room with us
on i've got an idea
let's pop him on here shall we
let's make a little let's make a little
let's make a little mumbo
we'll make a little mumbo again let's
get his mustache on here oh there it is
last time
it's brilliant we need to add these guys
yes
get some eyes
[Laughter]
it's like it's like he never left
mumbai you made it to the meeting how
great okay right
mumbo isgal has an idea to share with us
hmm yes i got a pitch mambo oh yeah
you're gonna love it you're gonna love
it
right am i am i can i pitch something
green you're the ceo and i feel like out
of my place here but i do have a pitch
okay i'm listening mumbo's listening i
want to build
sahara prime
i want a section of sahara that you can
buy into through a membership a lifetime
membership and that grants you access to
super cool stuff like kits and stuff and
then
also
it's just faster delivery so
they pay us
to buy more stuff
exactly they pay us to do more stuff
yes
that's the best okay that's the best
marketing campaign ever that's
internally that's how you do business so
they pay us to to pay us to buy more
stuff
and sahara does take a little while so a
faster buying method genius it's genius
what do you think mambo
[Music]
let me have a cup of tea
he seems to love it
mate
[Laughter]
follow me i have the perfect okay
because we're gonna take we're gonna
take mumbo with us oh we're
gonna take mumbai with us at least
the mobile mobile mustache has to come
with us
okay so one of the main things with
sahara with the sahara prime idea would
be delivery speed so what i'm thinking
is we raise a new impressive
but smaller more exclusive
warehouse and we separate it from the
original warehouse
okay so where are you you're thinking
over here seeing i'm thinking yeah
in this very corner and this is up to
you because you are the master architect
but if we can have something poke out
from this building and sort
i don't know how much redstone i don't
want to build it and then you go this
isn't enough space how big yeah
i haven't done the calculator not very
big like 21 blocks by 20. if you lay out
the blocks like this for me and then
i'll i'll build the warehouse
and then we'll get sahara sahara prime
we can't do sahara prime it's too close
to competitors on the interwebs
oh i see sahara
sahara rapid
fire sahara quick no again that's taken
sahara now
saharan saharan saharan africa i like
that sahara now
now
what do you think mumbo yeah what's your
opinion about this
i love this new version of bumble he's
agreeing with everything we do
so what do we do with um
mumbo wait
wait
wait hold on wait there we go there we
go what do we do with mumbo
what do you mean
in what regards in sahara now
no i'm thinking
oh well
he doesn't know what we've done he
doesn't know he doesn't oh
we could we could hide mumbo's mustache
somewhere
i see what you mean yeah i see think
about what i'm putting down you know we
should definitely do that is it so cause
i i remind me of the rules of this thing
is it so that he has to acquire that
mustache
this is his actual mustache and he's got
to find it if he wants it back on his
face
okay let's let's let's put mumbo back
where he was
that does yeah that does give him uh uh
a reason to be here
let's put let's put that back okay it
looks just like him it does it does how
did i go i got an idea the arms wait
hold on hold on i got an idea
there we go
[Laughter]
man i sure love turning up to meetings
there we go so when he finds it he's
gonna realize why we've done this
hopefully bye mumbo good luck
thank you for agreeing with us and keep
the room keep the room warm
so it looks like sahara now is a project
for another episode maybe next episode
we can work on that because right now
scar invited me and a few others to play
hide and seek over there and i think
they're actually waiting on me so i'm
gonna fly over there now yep there they
are they're all waiting for me let's
give this a go i've not played hide and
seek in minecraft probably ever so let's
uh see what oh whoa this guy was
straight up
[Laughter]
that's um
that's a
that's a little bit creepy
welcome to creeper wood with good times
with scar
that is really weird
all right all right let's play this game
howdy partners and welcome to creep why
don't i have my camera i was laughing
because i didn't know which i didn't
know which sky was talking
so we're playing hide and tag so it's
hide and seek with a little bit of a
twist in that when you go and hide the
seeker
has to hit you with a crossbow all right
guys so here's the rules
head over here get yourselves an outfit
you put on the leather armor you put
that on then you grab yourself some dyes
so you can die yourself however you
please
and then you grab yourself invisibility
potion and then your corresponding
player head you can mix and match player
heads that's okay that's part of the
rules i don't have to be me
i'm telling you
[Laughter]
and then of course the seeker which i'm
gonna be the seeker because i know the
hiding spots and we can have some fun
with that let's go you're gonna be very
easy to find all right gentlemen i will
be in here for two minutes using the
restroom will you guys hide
all right let's go
boys where are we going to go are we are
we going to go together we we maximize i
don't know that that sounds
like he can only listen he can only
shoot one of us at a time right so yeah
we we
we skarp her
take what someone takes one for the team
but we're difficult to find
i wonder how him can someone come and
check how hidden i am
um
i can literally i cannot find him right
now okay oh don't say anything can he
hear us that's true no he can't hear us
he can't hear us okay good
he's got the headphones on yeah loud
metal music okay as soon as he as soon
as he comes back in we all say we're
hidden behind the piano okay i'm inside
tango tech's skin are you actually
yes should we type in chat we're ready
yeah i guess so i thought he would come
out right now ready
and he's coming after you now i'm hidden
behind the tango statue i'm i'm
i cannot believe
i cannot believe how you just sold a
brother out like that
oh my goodness no my aim is so bad
it was terrible scar i i waited for the
perfect moment to move
oh
i saw some little feetsies
little
feetsies no no get back here
[Laughter]
has there been a horrible betrayal here
in the cowboy lands i think this guy's
really upset i couldn't see someone who
who did he get did
you wouldn't hurt your good old boy pal
well you've only got three and a half
minutes of invisibility potion left what
about wren right and you've got to give
a you've got to give a little hint hints
around
we found ren already but we wanted to
find you first what you found right now
no no
floating parade just is moving no no
you're not the seeker
i don't care
not fair
[Laughter]
someone's salty because they told me
where they were hiding
am i still in does this count
yeah
he hasn't found you so
if you can stay alive for one minute and
12 seconds
if he's already got oh
no
ren apparently has mastered the dodge
and the weave
i'm dodging i'm weaving like nobody's
business up in here my dude you'll never
catch me
please dang it
i'm out
all right come on 45 seconds 45 seconds
wait did we pay any diamonds for this
game
no you're supposed to pay five but i
don't think we went over those
i
i'll yeah
i got sold out
no
out of time
how did you not see me
don't tell me you were wearing a red
shirt dude i didn't even have an
invisibility potion because i died
already i was literally like this
and i saw him bounce over me
so i um win some diamonds
i know we didn't put anything in the
park oh come on okay
are we good are we ready to go guys i do
not want green to know where i'm hiding
this time okay
all right i got an escape plan if he
comes too close i'm out no not cool not
cool not cool i'm not ready i haven't
got a place
[Music]
i can't be there i can't be a dodging
and a weave in him the whole time either
ready i've got a place oh man i'm so
dead
ready or not here i come boys
hmm that came out a little bit creepier
than i anticipated
that did a little bit
all right lads where are you at
no not at all
this is actually really hard
i think you've been past green a few
times oh green there's green there's
spruce everywhere
wait a minute i love green
are you guys even in this arena right
now
also why is this so hard
scar why did you make this game so hard
dude one of you oh
agreeing do you uh did you run out of
invisibility there
you even thought of invisibility a
little hint no i'm not out of
invisibility oh wait okay
then i gotta say that was a pro move
green
wait did i just run straight past you
yeah you had a little dance with someone
with you no
this is not right
how was this how has this happened i got
a little uh confession to make i i never
actually found a hiding spot
what
you're making me feel like an idiot
oxygen to the brain man green hasn't
even hit
brett didn't even hide dude
what do you mean you didn't hide he
hasn't hit him he's been running around
i was invisible my invisibility person
ran out that's it i won i'm i'm out of
it i'm out i don't want to play this
anymore i'm done i'm gonna be seeking
drink the potions in three two one
i'm gonna mute let me know when you're
ready
all right they're ready okay i'm in a
very very dangerous spot it's dangerous
you say right ready i know here i come i
do not want for the queen
good luck queen and country
i feel like i'm gonna fall any second i
shouldn't look anxious
i didn't even know you could stand on
this thing
oh i'm hurting i'm hurt i'm gonna
abandon my spot
no
that's a quick fine
no you can't you can't get a guy that
was drowning
oh did you stop he was hiding in the
water
i tested that with aqua affinity
pretty good escape i gotta say no scar
come back here
no i'll praise be the praise be the
queen
one down
one day
bring it on dude scott for the inventor
of this game you're not doing too well
well i mean
i'm trying not to overdo my hunting
spots a little bit but no i actually
thought that water trap was gonna be
perfect but
yeah
oh you caught me immediately then
oh that's part of the rain diggity dark
nice friends left if anything has become
clearer today it is that i am the best
at this
game i've already walked past him he say
coming soon boys tutorial how to play
hide and seek
has anyone got some food for me
no oh my goodness i can't see me
that's that's you know that's that's
teetering on the on the edge of spoiler
age what are you using he's got 20
seconds 20 seconds
yes 15.
oh victory has never felt so sweet
oh man 10. i'm actually sweating i'm so
happy right now
five
four
three
come on
one oh he was close by the end
he was close to the end yes
hide and seek was a lot of fun and we
actually played for well over an hour
but you know
an hour of hide and seek makes for a
very very long episode of hermitcraft so
i did put in some highlights hopefully
you enjoyed the mini game if you want us
to play some more hide and seek then do
let us know but it might be more of a
streamy kind of game
anyway that was a lot of fun thank you
very much scarf for your efforts on that
mini game i can't wait to play again
sometime i had a lot of fun however we
are starting to run out of time for this
episode so
just to finish off i want to show you
what i plan on doing over here
so i have actually flattened this out as
i showed you earlier in the episode but
what i'm actually going to be doing here
is making a brand new minigame which is
why i need all this space
now i'm actually going to be making
rather weirdly a build that i've made on
my channel once before
and that is a haunted mansion i made
like three years ago like a really
really long time ago but for some reason
the design just works really well
with what i want to make so what i'm
going to do is just quickly lay out the
foundations of this house because it's
actually going to take me a really long
time to make this particular build let
alone the mini game on the inside of it
so this is where i'm going to leave you
thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you enjoyed today's
episode and we will kick off the next
episode
by
well hopefully finishing off this
particular build so i'll see you in the
next episode thank you very much for
watching everyone and good
bye